Finding Aid for Jennifer Granholm papers, 1992-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Communications Division
  - Director’s Files (Liz Boyd)
    - Speeches
      - Materials Annotated by Jennifer Granholm
        - 2004
          - Cool Cities Announcement, Detroit (Box 193)
          - Manufacturing Lobby Day Press Briefing (Box 193)
          - Granholm Leadership Fund Event (Box 193)
          - Interview Regarding Former Governor William Milliken (Box 193)
          - Pfizer Announcement (Box 193)
          - National Urban League Conference (Box 193)
          - Michigan Army National Guard Annual Review and Memorial (Box 193)
          - Governors’ Interstate Indian Council (GIIC) (Box 193)
          - New Product Dedication -- Dodge Dakota and Jeep Grand Cherokee (Box 193)
          - Consular Corps Reception (Box 193)
          - Introduction of Senator John Kerry (Box 193)
          - Governor’s Education Summit Speech (Box 193)
          - Ryder Cup Gala (Box 193)
          - Commission on Higher Education and Economic Growth Report (Box 193)
          - Byrnes Institute undated (Box 193)
          - Graduation Ceremony for the Michigan Youth Challenge Academy (Box 193)
        - 2005
          - North American International Auto Show (NAIAS) “2020 Future Visions of Tomorrow’s Automobile,” Symposium (Box 193)
          - National Governors Association (NGA) (Box 193)
          - Michigan Jobs and Investment Act Press Conference (Box 193)
          - Michigan Education Association (MEA) -- Annual Bargaining, Political Action and Public Relations Conference (Box 193)
          - Great Lakes Manufacturing Forum (Box 193)
          - American Constitution Society, Michigan Lawyers Chapter Kickoff (Box 193)
          - 8th Annual Michigan State University Education Conference (Box 193)
          - Michigan Celebrates Small Business Awards Dinner (Box 193)
          - American Muslim Society Grand Opening (Box 193)
          - La SED Annual Recognition Luncheon (Box 193)
          - LIVE Radio Interview -- WCHB 1200 AM (Box 193)
          - Breakfast for Your Committee (Box 193)
          - DaimlerChrysler (DCX) Manufacturing Symposium (Box 193)
          - TANA Conference (Box 193)
          - Agriculture and Michigan’s Economy (Box 193)
          - Community Development Block Grant (CDBG) Announcement Delhi Charter Township (Box 193)
          - Early Childhood Investment Corporation (ECIC) -- First Board of Directors Meeting (Box 193)
          - ACC Civic and Humanitarian Awards Gala (Box 193)
          - Emily’s List 20th Anniversary Gala (Box 193)
          - Affirmations Capital Campaign Groundbreaking (Box 193)
          - “50 Years and Counting” (Box 193)
          - “Leading Change and Renewal: Strategies When the Stakes are High,” at Harvard University, John F. Kennedy School of Government (Box 193)
        - 2007
          - Constitution and Resolution of Budget Deficits (Box 193)
          - WJR, Detroit -- Live Interview (Box 193)
          - The Plan for Michigan’s Economy (Box 193)
          - Saginaw County Democratic Party’s Fall Banquet (Box 193)
          - Radio Briefing Memo: Budget Agreement Radio Interviews (Box 193)
          - Radio Interviews with Ron Jolly, WTCM and Michael Patrick Shields, WJIM (Box 193)
          - Call with Phil Power Regarding Kennecot Mine (Box 193)
          - Proposed Ideas for Film Industry Incentives (Box 193)
          - State Children’s Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) -- Call with Senator Stabenow (Box 193)
          - “Michigan Response to Hate” Conference (Box 193)
          - Governor Phone Call with Kraft Foods, Inc. (Box 193)
          - National Organization for Women (NOW) Conference (Box 193)
          - National Governors Association (NGA) (Box 193)
        - 2008
          - Toyota Technical Center (Box 193)
          - Electoral College Meeting (Box 193)
          - Dropout Prevention Summit (Box 193)
    - News reports, press conferences, interviews, etc.
      - Videocassettes (VHS)
        - 1998-2002
          - Off the Record, May 29, 1998 (Box 194)
          - Midland Bar Association Law Day Luncheon 1999 (Box 194)
            (includes a letter from James E. Wilson)
          - Comcast Newsmakers: Attorney General Jennifer Granholm on Hate Crimes and Racial Profiling February 19, 2002 (Box 194)
          - Fairlane Sunrise Rotary April 23, 2002 (Box 194)
          - “Gubernatorial Candidates” -- The Morning Show II/WJR-AM Detroit May 31, 2002 (Box 194)
        - 2003
          - Bart Howley Show (Box 195)
          - B’nai B’rith Great Lakes Region Presents Jewish Community Council Honors David Techner “Activist of the Year” with Michigan Governor Jennifer Granholm, 2 tapes (Box 195)
          - DaimlerChrysler Plant in Dundee (Box 195)
          - Department of Labor and Economic Growth Premiere (Box 195)
          - Editor’s Notepad (Box 195)
          - “Evening with the Governor” (Box 195)
          - Governor Granholm Forum (Box 195)
          - Governor Granholm Public Service Announcement -- Travel Michigan: “All Jump” (Box 195)
          - Governor’s Press Conference: Cabinet Appointments -- Gloria Jeff and Lisa Webb Sharpe (Box 195)
          - Homeland Security Conference -- TV-4 News Stories (Box 195)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation Today 71 (Box 195)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation Today 75 (Box 195)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation Today 77 (Box 195)
          - Michigan Government Television Programming (MGTV) Forum -- Michigan Public Radio Call-In Program with Governor Granholm (Box 195)
          - “Michigan in the Balance” (WILX-TV) (Box 195)
          - Michigan Inauguration (Box 195)
          - Michigan Inauguration, Governor’s Residences (Box 195)
          - “Michigan’s Budget” (WDIV-TV) (Box 195)
          - Press Conference -- Ribbon Cutting for New TCOM Bridge Upgrading a Videoconferencing Network (Box 195)
          - Project Great Start, “To Have a Great Future” (Box 195)
          - Saginaw County Department of Health, 75th Anniversary Presentation (Box 195)
          - Spotlight, Governor Milliken (Box 195)
          - State of the State Address (Box 195)
          - State of the State Address (second copy) (Box 195)
          - Switched! -- Episode 107 (Rudy/Adam) (Box 195)
          - TC City Commission Meeting (Box 195)
          - “The Budget Crisis” -- WOOD-TV 8 Special Broadcast (Box 195)
          - Town Hall Special -- Granholm (Box 195)
          - Travel Michigan Media Tour -- TV Clips (Box 195)
          - Unemployment Special (Box 195)
          - We Make a Difference -- United Auto Workers (UAW) Community Action Conference (CAP) (Box 195)
          - WGVU-TV Newsmakers: Governor Granholm (Box 195)
        - 2004
          - Am I Right?-- Detroit Public TV Episode 148 (Box 196)
          - Carl Levin Birthday Video (Box 196)
          - Comcast Newsmakers -- Governor Granholm (Box 196)
          - Community Meeting: Dioxin -- City of Midland (Box 196)
          - Democratic National Convention (DNC) 2004 Speakers-Governor Granholm -- The Daily Show, Comedy Central (Box 196)
          - Ernst & Young Entrepreneur of the Year Awards, Parts 1 & 2 -- Michigan Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 196)
          - Girls to Governors -- Interview with Michigan Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 196)
            (includes a letter from the Youth Channel/Future Culture Group)
          - Governor Granholm and Watersmeet School District Nimrods (Box 196)
          - Governor Granholm on Bill Maher (Box 196)
          - Granholm -- Car Seminar (Box 196)
          - The Health Care Association of Michigan and Michigan Center for Assisted Living Present “Reach for the Stars -- Visions of Excellence” (Box 196)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation Today 80 (Box 196)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation Today 81 (Box 196)
          - Skubick (Box 196)
          - Street Beat Interview (Box 196)
          - Tavis Smiley -- Governor Jennifer Granholm/Jeff Stetson (Box 196)
          - To the Point, February 1 (Box 196)
          - To the Point, February 13 (Box 196)
          - VisionWorks/Campbell & Co., America’s Promise Public Service Announcement,” 2 Versions (Box 196)
          - WGVU Newsmakers 419 -- Conversation with Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 196)
          - Wayne County Regional Educational Service Agency (RESA) (Box 196)
        - 2005
          - Capitol Report -- Central Michigan University (CMU) Public TV, Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 177)
          - Consumer’s Corner 2005-9, Michigan State Housing Development Authority -- Homeless Awareness Week (Box 177)
          - Detroit -- Michigan Matters (Box 177)
          - Flashpoint (Box 177)
          - Governor Granholm’s Rosa Parks Funeral (Box 177)
          - Labor Day Bridge Walk, Unedited Footage (Box 177)
          - Media Meet 505, Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 177)
          - Media Meet 547, Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 177)
          - Michigan Hate Groups (Box 177)
          - Michigan Department of Transportation (MDOT) Centennial Video: 1905-2005 A Century of Michigan Travel (Box 177)
          - Off the Record, Governor Granholm (Box 177)
          - Press Conference -- Governor Granholm and Senate and House Leadership Announce an Agreement on a Jobs Creation Package (Box 177)
          - Spotlight on the News (Box 177)
          - State of the State Address (Box 177)
        - 2006
          - Am I Right? 327, Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 177)
          - Backstage Pass and The Last Lap (Box 177)
          - Consumer’s Corner 2006-1 (Box 177)
          - Consumer’s Corner 2006-2 -- Great Jobs in Michigan (Box 177)
          - Detroit Area Council, Boy Scouts of America -- Distinguished Citizen Dinner Honoring Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 177)
          - Flashpoint Roundtable (Box 177)
          - Governor Jennifer Granholm Press Tour (Box 177)
          - HKO Media, United Solar Ovonic Greenville, Michigan Press Conference (Box 177)
          - Michigan Governor Jennifer Granholm, WAMU Radio, American University, Audio cassette (Box 177)
          - Press Conference, Governor Granholm (Box 177)
          - Public Service Announcement, Michigan’s Minimum Wage Increase (Box 177)
          - Sesame Workshop -- NGA Healthy Habits PSAs Governor Granholm, Betacam SP Cassette (Box 177)
          - Tax Policy (Box 177)
          - To the Point (Box 177)
          - West Michigan Week 2604 (Box 177)
        - 2007
          - Comcast Newsmakers -- Governor Granholm (Box 177)
          - Conversation with Governor Granholm -- Central Michigan University (CMU) Public TV (Box 177)
          - Pierce: Kidwitness News -- Governor Granholm (Box 177)
            (includes a greeting card)
          - Spotlight on the News -- Governor Granholm (Box 177)
        - Undated
          - American Axel Grand Opening (Box 178)
          - America’s Promise (Box 178)
          - Attorney General Jennifer Granholm Tours Empire Mine (Box 178)
          - Business Now, A WBTE Production -- Governor Granholm of Michigan, 2 tapes (Box 178)
          - Committee to Protect Our Schools -- Granholm/Johnson (TV), Granholm/Johnson “Live” (Radio) (Box 178)
          - Cool Cities Meeting at Wayne State (Box 178)
          - Governor on Capitol Connection with Rep. Wojno, Macomb County (Box 178)
          - Homeless Awareness Week (Box 178)
          - Inside Macomb -- Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 178)
          - The Job Show 799 (Box 178)
          - Job Show Segment -- Cool Cities (Box 178)
          - Michigan Army National Guard (Box 178)
          - Michigan Military Family Relief Fund Public Service Announcement (Tax) (Box 178)
          - Michigan State Police (MSP) Graduation Ceremony -- Jennifer Granholm, Governor, State of Michigan (Box 178)
          - “Regarding Lt. Governor John Cherry” (Remarks by Jennifer Granholm) (Box 178)
          - Spotlight on the News -- Jennifer Granholm (Box 178)
          - Spotlight on the News -- Land Use (Box 178)
          - Spotlight on the News -- “Newsmaker” Governor Jennifer Granholm (Box 178)
          - Spotlight, “Newsmakers of the Year” (Box 178)
          - Traverse Bay Area Intermediate School District -- “Way to Grow” Early Education Program (Box 178)
          - Teamsters for Granholm (Box 178)
          - Tipping to Cool Conference -- Jennifer Granholm, Governor, State of Michigan, Betacam SP Cassette (Box 178)
          - Tribute to Excellence -- Remarks by Jennifer Granholm, Governor, State of Michigan (Box 178)
          - United Auto Workers (UAW)/Rainbow PUSH (People United to Serve Humanity) Second Annual Community Symposium -- Remarks by Governor Jennifer M. Granholm (Box 178)
          - Violent Video Games, WILX TV (Box 178)
          - Welcome to Chinese Business People Meeting with the Detroit Chinese-American Business Association -- Remarks by Jennifer Granholm, Governor, State of Michigan (Box 178)
          - We’ve Got Issues, Eric Green (Box 178)
      - Digital video and photographs
        - 2003
          - “Ask the Governor" (760 AM WJR Radio) 2003
          - Governor Granholm and First Gentleman Dan Mulhern on Central Michigan Public Radio 2003
          - Inauguration
            - Photographs (Volume 1, 3, and 4; files on Volume 2 were corrupted) 2003
            - Thumbnail images 2003
          - Michigan Public Radio: Governor Granholm Call-In 2003
        - 2004
          - Governor Granholm on “Mojo in the Morning,” 2004
          - Mackinac Bridge Walk with Governor 2004
          - Military Family Holiday Relief Fund PSA 2004
          - The Frank Beckmann Show: Jennifer Granholm and Jeanne Shaheen discussing the 2004 election, 2004
        - 2005
          - 1776th Military Police (MP) Company, Hurricane Katrina Relief 2005
          - Dave Barber Show: “Toyota Coming to Flint,” (Supertalk 1750 AM), 2005
          - Detroit Economic Club Luncheon: “A Vision for Michigan’s Economic Future” (remarks by Governor Granholm) 2005
          - Foreign Correspondents’ Club of Japan, Jennifer Granholm Professional Luncheon 2005
          - Governor Granholm Press Conference 2005
          - Governor Granholm Weekly Radio Address/Podcast (Topic: state fairs and agriculture) 2005
          - Interlochen Public Radio Island Cabin Disks: Governor Jennifer Granholm 2005
          - Michigan National Guard 126th Press Camp Headquarters: Hurricane Katrina Relief 2005
          - Michigan Public Radio: Governor Granholm Call-In 2005
        - 2006
          - American Black Journal (Detroit Public Television), 2006
          - Commission on Spanish Speaking Affairs (COSSA) Meeting at the Capitol 2006
          - Critical Issues: “Still Biting the Bullet” (Episode 104 with Governor Jennifer Granholm), 2006
          - Detroit Free Press 2006
          - “Dow OnSite”: Granholm at Dow Chemical Company Michigan Operations Site Rededication 2006
          - Google Press Conference, 2006
          - Governor Granholm on “The Dave and Geri Morning Show” (105.3 FM-WHTS, Grand Rapids) 2006
          - Governor Jennifer Granholm Press Tour (Detroit Public TV) 2006
          - Life Happens with David Carrier! (Special Guest Jennifer Granholm), May 20, 2006
          - Mackinac Bridge Run 2006
          - Mackinac Policy Conference Detroit Regional Chamber General Session: A Conversation with Governor Granholm (Michigan Government Television Programming) 2006
          - Mentors, Mentees, and the Governor’s Family (during Labor Day Mackinac Bridge Run events) 2006
          - “Michigan Celebrates Small Business” (address by Governor Granholm) 2006
          - Pure Michigan 2006
          - Pure Michigan Vignettes 2006
          - Richard H. Austin Building Dedication 2006
          - The Big Story: Ask the Governor 2006
          - The Frank Beckmann Show: Interview with Governor Granholm (760 AM WJR), 2006
        - 2007
          - Andy Dillon Press Conference (Democratic legislators economic plans) 2007
          - Conversations with Judy Woodruff (Guest: Governor Jennifer Granholm), 2007
          - Governor Granholm and Lt. Governor John Cherry: Inaugural Open House at the Flint Institute of Arts (Comcast Channel 17) 2007
          - Governor Granholm Interview with Detroit Free Press 2007
          - Governor Granholm on “The Dave and Geri Morning Show” (105.3 FM, WHTS, Grand Rapids) 2007
          - Governor Granholm Q & A at Constitution Hall 2007
          - Governor Granholm Round Table at Brighton District Library 2007
          - Governor Granholm Visits Macomb Intermediate School District (MISD) 2007
          - Habitat for Humanity, National Governors Association Conference, Build Photos 2007
          - National Governor’s Association Summer Meeting 2007
          - National Science Foundation International Laboratory Expansion Dedication 2007
          - Spotlight on the News: Governor Granholm, 2007
          - State of the State Address 2007
          - To the Point (WOOD-TV), 2007
          - WGVU Newsmakers (Episode 707): Dan Mulhern 2007
          - WGVU Newsmakers (Episode 740) 2007
        - 2008
          - Currently Speaking: Governor Granholm Interview (Episode 916), 2008
          - Governor Granholm on CNBC’s Squawk Box 2008
          - Governor Granholm on NBC’s Today Show 2008
          - “Granholm’s Green Tour” (Northwestern Michigan College, Michigan Technological University, and Traverse City) 2008
          - Green Meadow Farms 2008
          - Michigan Milk Producers Association 2008
          - National Governors Association Winter Meeting (includes plenary addresses by Thomas Friedman and John Doerr) 2008
          - Obama’s First Press Conference (includes Governor Granholm) 2008
          - Owosso Real People 2008
          - Spotlight on the News: Governor Granholm, 2008
          - State of the State Address 2008
          - Various images: House of Representatives, Democratic Communications Photos, State of the State, Booksellers Roundtable, Jenike and LaKisha, and Lt. Governor John Cherry 2008
        - 2009
          - Detroit Economic Club National Summit: Vision for America (General Session, Day 2) 2009
          - Michigan Recovery & Reinvestment Plan, Governor Granholm’s Visit to Delta College 2009
          - State of the State Address 2009
          - West Michigan Week (Episode 2906), 2009
        - 2010
          - Governor Granholm and LG Chemical with President Obama and at Charter House Innovations 2010
          - Governor Granholm at Capitol Farmers Market 2010
          - Governor Granholm at General Election Aviation (Grand Rapids) 2010
          - Governor Granholm Bill Signings (SB 1014 HB s 5920 and 6226), 2010
          - Governor Granholm Chevy Volt Test Drive 2010
          - Governor Granholm, Habitat Restore Bill Signing 2010
          - Governor Granholm in Benton Harbor 2010
            - Photographs
            - Video
          - Helping Hardest Hit Homeowners Program Announcement (Lansing) 2010
          - Kalamazoo River Oil Spill: Aerial views and images of Governor Granholm's briefing with the Environmental Protection Agency in Battle Creek 2010
          - Labor Day Bridge Run, Straits of Mackinac 2010
          - Michigan Supreme Court Announcement (Justice Elizabeth “Betty” Weaver announces her resignation) 2010
          - Solidica (Ann Arbor), Governor Granholm 2010
          - State of the State Address 2010
        - Undated
          - “Michigan: Creating the Advanced Battery Capital of the World,” undated
          - “Michigan: The Upper Hand,” undated
  - General Office Records
    The General Office Records subseries documents public relations activities for a wide range of the Granholm administration's initiatives, including the 2002-2003 transition, the First Gentleman, and the Cool Cities program. This series also contains transcripts for Granholm's radio addresses, special greetings letters sent to constituents, Op-eds, photographs, and an Article Database that contains electronic news clippings from 2003-2007.
    - Transition Materials 2002-2003
      - Correspondence
      - Inaugural
      - Medicaid Summit
      - Miscellaneous Documents
      - Pictures
      - Press Releases
      - Speeches and Remarks
    - Accomplishments 2003-2010
    - Articles database: copies of articles, editorials, and opinion pieces related to Michigan and the Granholm administration 2003-2007
    - Articles of interest: summaries of newspaper articles and editorials 2007-2010
    - Audio Files: interviews, press conferences, and news events
      - Governor Granholm
        - 2004
        - 2005
        - 2006
        - 2007
        - 2008
        - 2009
        - 2010
      - Lieutenant Governor John Cherry
        - 2008
        - 2009
      - Other recordings
        - February-silver recorder circa 2006-2010
        - “General” recordings circa 2006-2010
        - “Unknown” recordings circa 2006-2010
    - Audio Transcripts (includes 2007 employee recognition week), 2005-2010
    - Budget: issue papers, talking points, presentations, etc 2004-2010
    - Cherry Commission on Higher Education and Economic Growth 2004
    - Emergency Financial Advisory Panel Final Report 2007
    - Executive Directives 2003-2010
    - Executive Orders 2003-2010
    - Executive Proclamations 2007
    - Final Releases of Statements, Reports, and Other Documents 2003-2010
    - First Gentleman Materials
      - Advisories 2003-2008
      - Memoranda and Letters 2003
      - Mentor Michigan 2003-2009 (scattered)
      - Op Eds 2003-2008 (scattered)
      - Press Releases 2003-2008
      - Talking Points 2003-2005
    - Forewords (to books) 2005, 2007
    - Governor Initiatives
      - Cool Cities 2006
      - General 2005, 2007
      - Jobs Today, Jobs Tomorrow
        - General 2005-2008
        - Jobs for Michigan Fund 2006
        - Jobs Today Initiative 2005
        - Jobs and Investment Act 2005
        - Michigan Business Tax 2006
        - New Merit Scholarship 2005-2006
      - No Worker Left Behind 2007
      - One Stop Shop 2009
      - Pure Michigan 2007
      - Reform Documents 2007
      - Save the Dream 2008
      - Upper Hand Campaign 2006
    - Graphics
      - Governor’s Seals 2000, 2003
      - Recovery 2009
      - State of the State 2003-2010, 8 folders
    - Letters
      - Employee Communications 2003-2010
      - Outgoing correspondence 2003-2010
      - Received (scanned images) 2004-2010
    - Mackinac Conference: talking points, presentations, press releases, etc, for the annual Mackinac Policy Conference sponsored by the Detroit Regional Chamber 2003-2008
    - National Governors Association Summer Meeting (Traverse City): correspondence, Frequently Asked Questions, promotional materials, etc. 2007
    - Newsletters (electronic versions from the Governor’s website) 2003-2008
    - Op-Eds 2003-2010
      - 2007
      - Affirmative Action 2008
      - Auto Industry 2003, 2008
      - Benton Harbor 2008
      - Cesar Chavez 2004
      - Cities of Promise 2006
      - Cool Cities 2004, 2006
      - Dearborn Times Herald 2006
      - Detroit Free Press 2008-2010
      - Detroit News 2004-2010
      - Education-Scholarships 2006, 2008
      - Employees 2003
      - Flint Journal 2007
      - Grand Rapids Press 2006-2007
      - Huffington Post 2009-2010
      - General 2004-2010
      - Lansing State Journal 2005-2010
      - Michigan Chronicle 2004-2010
      - Newsweek 2008-2009
      - New York Times 2008, 2010
      - Ramadan 2003
      - Single Business Tax (SBT) 2003, 2006
      - Snowmobiles 2005
      - Water 2004, 2006
    - Other Press Releases: topics include environmental issues, the passage of legislation, mental health, university appointments, etc. 2004-2005
    - Photographs
      - Albums
        - Governor 2003-2010